ecowatch.com 2015-06-28

# Privacy Policy

EcoWatch will never, under any circumstances, sell, trade or make public your personal information, unless you designate otherwise. All personal information you provide will remain confidential. You will always have the option to edit the information provided to us or to have your personal information removed from our records.

**Email Newsletters**

After subscribing to EcoWatch’s email list, users will receive email newsletters and other occasional announcements from EcoWatch and our partners. Users can unsubscribe from email newsletters at any time.

**Traffic Data**

When you visit EcoWatch, our systems collect basic information about your computer, including: IP address (your computer’s unique signature), operating system (e.g., Windows 95), browser software (e.g., Microsoft Internet Explorer, Netscape), Internet Service Provider (e.g., AOL). We also collect information about what you view on the site. This information helps provide information about our readership and allows us to better understand the EcoWatch community.

**Advertising**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

**Use of Cookies**

EcoWatch employs cookies, which are small text files placed on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to count the number of visitors to our website; the cookie enables us to distinguish repeat visitors from new visitors. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your browser help file directions. If visitors decline cookies, some portions of our site that depend on cookies may be inaccessible or slower to access. Cookies also help us diagnose problems with our server.

**Discussion Forum**

EcoWatch uses the comment platform Disqus. Any information disclosed in these areas becomes publicly available, and therefore you should exercise caution when disclosing personal information.

**Survey**

EcoWatch will conduct voluntary surveys of site visitors to obtain demographic information about its readers. This information may be compiled and shared with third parties, but no personal details will be traceable or associated with specific readers.

**Petitions**

EcoWatch hosts two kinds of petitions: petitions run by EcoWatch lobbying government organizations and/or corporations to improve environmental standards and paid petitions sponsored by third parties, typically nonprofits.

For EcoWatch sponsored and 3rd party petitions, the target of the petition and EcoWatch will receive the information provided by the signer.

On petitions that run on EcoWatch, there is a checkbox below the personal information to opt into various newsletters and memberships including from our sponsors. Sponsors will only receive personal information provided if the user leaves the box opted-in. EcoWatch reserves the right to subscribe all signers who opt in to any offer on a petition to its daily newsletter. If a user does not wish to receive such communications and offers, they can uncheck the box on the petition, or unsubscribe from any newsletter or membership at anytime.

**Links to Other Sites**

EcoWatch contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

**Children’s Guidelines**

Protecting the rights of children is important to us. As a result, we do not collect or maintain any information from individuals we know to be under 13 years old, and no part of EcoWatch is intended to attract anyone under 13.

**Other Disclosure of Personal Information**

EcoWatch will not use or disclose your personal information without your consent, except (i) as described in this privacy policy or (ii) as required by law, court order or as requested by other government or law enforcement authority. This policy does not protect information you post in comments or other public forum within our website.

**Contacting EcoWatch**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding these policies, you may send an email to EcoWatch via this [online form](http://ecowatch.com/about/contact-us/).  All requests will be formally reviewed by our staff and will be answered within 48 hours.

EcoWatch  
46 E. 70th St  
New York, NY 10021

EcoWatch reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement at any time without notice, and only the current Privacy Statement may be deemed effective.
